Guide to the Administrative Papers of University College of Arts and Science, Office of the Dean RG.18.0.2
New York University Archives
- Series I: Correspondence, 1914-1935
  - SATC Course Handbooks: Auto Mechanics and Auto Drivers, ca.1918 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - SATC Course Handbooks: Carpenters, ca.1918 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - SATC Course Handbooks: Farries (Veterinary Assistant), ca.1918 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - SATC Course Handbooks: Sheet Metal Workers, ca.1918 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - SATC Course Handbooks: Surveyors, ca.1918 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - SATC Course Handbooks: Telephone Electricians, ca.1918 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - SATC Courses, 1917-1919 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - SATC Demobilization, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - SATC Final Report, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - SATC Final Report, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Schelling, Felix E., 1914-1920 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Schimer, E.F., 1915-1916 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Scholarships and Prizes, 1914-1919 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1916-1917 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Scholarship, Rhodes, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Schwab Property, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Schwartz, Arthur, 1918-1920 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Schwartz, Rabbi Solomon, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Schwarz, H. Stanley, 1914-1915 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Selective Admissions, Psychological and Personnel Testing, Americanism, Oaths of Allegiance (see also: publication- Colleges and Americanism, 1919), 1919-1920 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Selective Admissions, Psychological and Personnel Testing, Americanism, Oaths of Allegiance (see also: publication- Colleges and Americanism, 1919), 1921-1922 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Shao, Charles G., 1915-1919 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Siff, Louis, 1917-1919 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Sihler, Ernest Gottlieb, 1915-1921 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Simmons, John P., 1914-1921 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Sinberg, Samuel E., 1918-1922 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Slosson, Edwin E., 1915-1916 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Lewis Worthington, 1918-1921 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Snow, Charles H., 1915-1921 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Society of the Friends of the University of Rome, 1926-1933 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Somerville, Randolph, 1915-1921 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Sommer, Frank H., 1915-1921 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Sprague, George C., 1919 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Sprague, Leslie Willis, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - State Scholarship, 1914-1927 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Steel, Willis, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Steen-Moller, Paul, 1914-1916 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Steigman, B.M., 1916-1921 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Steigman, Otto, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Stein, Samuel P., 1916 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Stephens, Olin J., 1915-1919 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Stephens, Roderick, 1915-1921 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Stoddard, Dr. Francis Hovey, 1914-1920 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Stone, Charles A., 1915-1916 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Stout, Presley D., 1915-1916 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Streubel, Ernest J., 1916 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Student Accomodations: Report, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Student Activities, 1916-1924 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Student Activities--fraternities, 1918-1922 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Student Activities--Jewish, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Student Athletics-Welfare and Athletics, 1917-1926 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Student Athletics--Football Absences and Cheer, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Student Athletics--National Collegiate Association, 1916-1922 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Student Cabinet and Council, 1917-1924 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Student Military Service, 1916-1917 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Student Military Service, 1917-1919 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Student Military Service, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Student Military Service, 1918-1919 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Student Military Service-Letters of recommendation, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Student Military Service-Letters of recommendation, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Student Organization (NYU-University Heights), 1915-1924 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Student Personnel and Admissions, Director of: Letter concerning applications for the position, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Stuhr, William S., 1915-1917 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Stunkard, Horace M., 1919-1921 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Sullivan, James, 1915-1917 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Swan, Willard A., 1917-1920 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Sweet, Louis Matthews, 1916-1919 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: "T", undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Takehara, Tsuneta, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ten Eyck, Andrew, 1915-1920 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Thorne, Perley L., 1914-1921 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Tilton, Edgar, 1917-1919 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Tonsor, Charles A., 1914-1919 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Townsend, Atwood H., 1916-1923 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Tucker, Marion L., 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Tucker, Samuel, 1915-1922 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Turner, Samuel, 1915-1922 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Tuttle, Arthur S., 1918-1920 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: "U", undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Underwood, Horace H. (from Korea) some letters pertaining to World War I and others to his scholarship and for two other Korean students., 1914-1922 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - United Hospital Fund, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - United States Food Administration and other Agricultural Matters, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - University Senate, 1920-1932 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: "V", undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Vassar College Celebration, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Veterinary College, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Von Glahn, Theodore A., 1914 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: "W", undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Wade, Joseph H., 1921 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Wakefield, Arthur, 1920-1921 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Walker, Charles W., 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Walker, Ralph C., 1920-1922 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Wallace, Leonard F.W., 1919-1920 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - War Fund Campaign, 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - War Service Training Courses: Course Listing, 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Wartime Government Business Forms, 1919-1920 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Wartime Housing, Financial Matters, 1918-1919 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Wallin, William, 1915-1921 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Ward, Harrison F., 1920 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Waters, William E., 1914-1920 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Wayne, Elmer C., 1920 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Whitmore, E.W., 1914-1921 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Wildman, John R., 1915 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Wood, Earl Franklin, 1919-1920 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Woodbridge, F.J.E., 1914 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Woodman, J.E., 1914-1921 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Woodruff, Frank E., 1915-1917 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Woolsey, Albert, 1916-1919 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Woolworth, William S., 1914-1915 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: "Y", undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - YMCA, includes correspondence on war work, 1917-1921 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - YMCA, 1924-1930 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - YMCA, includes material about Freshman Camp, the Intercollegiate Branch, and Inter-Faith Council, 1931-1933 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Young, Karl (University of Wisconsin), 1916 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: "Z", undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Series II: Lecture Notes, Writings, Addresses, and Publications
  Lecture Notes, 1899-1915; Writings, Addresses, and Publications, 1909-1941, is a chronological file consisting of fragments of lectures, exam questions, and course outlines.
  - Lecture notes taken by Bouton in History XI taught by James Harvey Robinson of Columbia University. Bouton was working on his M.A. (received in 1900) [handwritten], 1899 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes, History XI [handwritten], 1899 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes, History XI (second term)[handwritten], 1900 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes for English Literary Prose(Composition and Literature)-taught by Bouton, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes for History of English Literature-taught by Bouton, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Analysis of phrase content in Stevenson's "Aes Triplex" with word, phrase, and sentence counts of verse, prose, etc., undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Analysis of word count, sentence count, and phrases of verse, prose, operas, etc., undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Writings: "The Oratorical Contest as a College Activity" [typed and annotated, published in 1911], ca.1911 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Writings: "Reminiscences from 1892" [typed and annotated], 1915 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Writings: The University Colege of Arts and Pure Science Centennial year 1831-1931 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Writings: The Past and the Present, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Writings: Higher Education: How Far and to Whom Should it be Made Available? To What Extent Should Government Provide It?, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Writings: "After the High School- What?" [typed and annotated], undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Writings: Armistice Day [re: Student Disarmament], undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Writings: The Blue Laws of the New Haven Colony [typed and annotated], undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Writings: College Spirit, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Writings: The Dean, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Writings: The Function of the College Liberal Arts in the New Era, as seen by a College Administrator, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Writings: Functions of a Dean, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Writings: Great Teachers and Their Work, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Writings: Note upon the Character of A. Trimmer by George Savile, Marquis of Halifax [typed and annotated], undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Writings: [some categories of the]Phenomena of Rhythm in English Prose [typed and annotated], undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Writings: Some notes on Amateur Book Collecting, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Writings: [Untitled], undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Writings: What Price Teaching?, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Writings: Who Should Receive a College Training?, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Writings: The Worth of a Training in Liberal Arts, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Addresses: To the Chancellor, Council, Alumni, Faculty, Undergraduates [perhaps upon becoming Dean, Nov 10] [typed and annotated], 1914 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Addresses: At Exercises in Memory of Professor William Kindall Gillett [typed and annotated], 1914 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Addresses: Notes for an address on the Importance of Method in Teaching and the Preparation of Instructors [typed and annotated], 1915 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Addresses: "The Culprit Fay: A Criticism" [typed and annotated with a Program for the Joseph Rodman Drake Memorial Celebration] later published in 1919, 1915 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Addresses: Address at the Opening of College, Sep 26, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Addresses: Remarks concerning Chancellor Emeritus MacCracken; at the Faculty Club [typed and annotated] later published in 1917, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Addresses: Address to the Graduates of the Evander Childs High School, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Addresses: Commencement Address at Adelphi College [typed and annotated], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Addresses: Remarks at the 25th Anniversary Dinner of the Amherst Class of 1896 [typed and annotated], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Addresses: Address to the Graduate of the Far Rockaway High School, Far Rockaway, NY, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Addresses: Address at the Inauguration of President Laird (at Albion College) "The College and the Hour", Oct 25 [typed and annotated], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Addresses: Opening Address, Sep 24, 1924 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Addresses: Remarks at Campaign Fund Dinner at Waldorf-Astoria, Feb 7, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Addresses: Suggested Materials for an Engrossed Resolution to be Presented by the Confernce of Deans, Fall, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Addresses: Conference of Universities, Dec 14, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Addresses: Ladies and Gentlemen and Members of the Graduating Class of the Dover High School, Jun 22, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Addresses: The University and the Modern Spirit, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum: of the Sub-Committee of the Civic Bureau of the Bronx Board of Trade, in regards to Litter in the Streets of the Bronx [typed and annotated], ca. 1917 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum[:] of Propositions embodying the Hopes and Wishers of the Dean for the Student Body as expressing at the Last Chapel Exercises, for the College Year, May 25, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Bibliography: Works of A.L. Bouton, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Publication: Commencement Number-The Amherst Student. Vol. 29, no. 33. "Class Oration," pp. 262-263, 1896 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Publications: "Is Culture Worthwhile?" [typed and annotated], ca. 1909 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Publications: "Is Culture Worthwhile?" [mimeographed and annotated], ca. 1909 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Publications: "Is Culture Worthwhile?" [printed], 1909 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Publications: "The Oratorical Contest as a College Activity" [printed], 1911 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Publications: Letter printed in 1918 Violet [printed], 1917 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Publications: "Colleges and the War" [photocopied article], 1918 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Publications: Remarks Concerning the late Chancellor Emeritus MacCracken; at the Faculty Club [printed in Alumni News, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Publications: "The Culprit Fay: A Criticism" [printed], 1919 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Publications: "The Colleges and Americanism" [printed], 1919 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Publications: "What Shall the Colleges Teach Today?" [printed in Endowment Fund Bulletin], 1920 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Publications: "The Social Importance of Student Failures" [printed in NYU Alumnus], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Publications: "The Homing Instinct in Lost Objects" [printed], 1926 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Publications: "The Greek Element in Modern Life" [printed], 1930 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Publications: "An Outline History of Transportation" [printed], 1934 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Memorial Service Programs for Archibald Lewis Bouton, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Memorial Papers by T.F. Jones and Albert S. Borgman, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous notes, etc., undated (Box 18, Folder 35)